# Konstantin Tenman

Software Engineer Tallinn, Estonia +372 511 1618 konstantin@tenman.ee https://github.com/ktenman https://www.linkedin.com/in/ktenman

### PROFILE

I have eight years of experience as a software developer, with a focus on Java. I commit to teamwork, building applications that undergo rigorous testing and seamless delivery. I love researching and staying updated with the latest technologies. I'm always searching for ways to improve my skills and make my work better.

## PROGRAMMING SKILLS

• Programming Languages: Java, TypeScript, Python Hibernate, JUnit, Mockito, WireMock, Kafka

Technologies: Spring Boot, Angular, Vue,

• Tools: AWS, PostgreSQL, Docker, Git, Maven, IntelliJ, Redis, Docker Swarm, Amazon ECS

• DevOps: Jenkins, GitHub Actions, GitLab CI/CD Languages: English, Estonian, Russian

### EXPERIENCE

• Bankera Tallinn, Estonia

Senior Software Engineer Jun 2022 - Present

As a key member of the Know Your Customer (KYC) team, I have led the development and maintenance of
microservices using Spring Boot and Java (versions 8 to 21), utilizing databases like Postgres and testing tools
such as Mockito, Wiremock, and Assert J. My contributions have been instrumental in building robust, scalable,
and effective solutions for financial services regulatory compliance.

# • University of Tartu

Tartu, Estonia

Teaching Assistant

Aug 2022 - Present

• Teaching courses on Object-Oriented Programming in Java, Web Application Development, and Enterprise System Integration, contributing to the academic growth of students.

• Monese Tallinn, Estonia

Technical Lead Engineer

Sep 2021 - Jun 2022

- Led the refactoring of a monolith into single-responsibility microservices within the Payments team.
   Spearheaded the architectural design of a strong customer authentication (SCA PSD2) solution and facilitated regular brainstorming sessions to foster team innovation and problem-solving.
- Played a pivotal role in interviewing and onboarding new team members, significantly contributing to team expansion and development.

• Monese

Technical Lead Engineer

London, United Kingdom

Jul 2020 - Sep 2021

• Systematically improved software performance and reduced operating costs, achieving a 50% reduction in monthly operating expenses for a critical application.

• Monese London, United Kingdom

Software Engineer

Zondon, Omted Kingdom

Mar 2019 - Jun 2020

- Identified and resolved production issues, significantly increasing revenue. A particular solution for a single customer uncovered a substantial profit gap.
- As a member of the Pricing team, I delivered new annual pricing functionality on time and without significant issues, and led research on decomposing a monolithic application into single-responsibility microservices.
- In the Joint Accounts team, I was responsible for designing and developing the core logic of the Joint Accounts feature.

• Monese
Software Engineer
Oct 2017 - Mar 2019

- Enhanced micro-service scalability by segregating database read and write operations.
- $\circ$  Successfully migrated 120M payments to a new queue-based Java micro-service, reducing the average response time from 60ms to 5ms.
- Introduced Angular 5 for internal tooling and improved seamless deployment on Amazon AWS.
- o Designed and developed a micro-service for Recurring Payments with a test coverage of up to 80%.

• Codeborne Tallinn, Estonia Apr 2017 - Oct 2017

Software Developer

o Developed responsive internet banking websites for major banking clients, including Bank "Saint-Petersburg" and the Czech online bank Expobank.cz.

• Enhanced team productivity and software quality by promoting best practices through code reviews, pair programming, and test-driven development.

• Knowit Tallinn, Estonia

Software Developer

Jun 2016 - Apr 2017

- Recognized as Employee of Q4, 2016 for outstanding contributions.
- Developed a full-stack, web-based application enabling users to create and search for services via Google Maps.

### **EDUCATION**

• Tartu University

Estonia

Master of Engineering (MEng) in Computer Science; GPA: 4.67/5;

- o Master's Thesis: "Developing a Web-Based Mini-Mental State Examination: Innovations in Accessibility and Efficiency for Cognitive Assessment."
- Recipient of Achievement and Specialisation stipends.

## • Tallinn University

Estonia

Bachelor of Science in Engineering (BSc) in Computer Science; GPA: 4.73/5; cum laude

- Bachelor's Thesis: "The Development of a Self-study Web Application Using Angular and Spring Boot."
- Recipient of Achievement and Specialisation stipends.